(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 10x03  Frontier in Space (Episode 3)
《神秘博士》老版第十季第三集 太空边境 (第三部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
JO: Ogrons!
You, come.
你们, 过来
What's next?
还有什么?
SECRETARY: The Historical Monuments Preservation Society
历史古迹保护协会
wants you to address their annual meeting on the 10th of January.
期望您出席他们在1月10日的周年活动
Mmm. Clashes with a cabinet meeting.
唔, 跟一堆的会议冲突了
Um, express apologies.
表达一下歉意
Congratulate them on their good work.
并对他们的工作成果表示祝贺
And there's an inquiry reportin on the anti-Draconian riots
这里是一份针对反龙族人骚乱的调查报告
in Peking last week.
上周发生在北京的
The petitioners seek your support for compensation.
受害人期望得到你支持他们在赔偿金方面的诉求
(PRESIDENT SIGHING)
Pass that onto the Treasury with my recommendation.
把这个转交给国库处理吧
All claims to be sympathetically considered.
他们的诉求都尽量酌情考虑一下
- Anything else? - General Williams requires an interview.
- 还有别的吗?  - Williams 将军期望能见您
- He says it's extremely urgent. - I see.
- 他说很紧急  - 我知道了
(DOOR BUZZING)
(GUN FIRING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Get down.
蹲下
That was close.
刚才好险
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
SECRETARY: General Williams to see you, madam.
Williams 将军来见您了, 夫人
Will you ask him to come in, please.
请他进来吧
(BUZZER BUZZING)
(DOOR OPENING)
Vanished. The Draconian kidnappers have completely disappeared.
消失了, 龙族匪徒完全不见了
No trace of them at all.
一点踪迹都没有
- Have some wine? - Thank you.
- 来点红酒不?  - 谢谢
Well, at least they didn't get away with it.
至少他们没能跟着跑掉
Those two traitors are back in their cell
and that's where they'll stay.
那两个叛徒, 他们被带回囚房了
The time has come for extreme measures.
是时候采取点极端措施了
I know. You want me to break off diplomatic relations.
我知道, 你想让我断绝外交关系
I want more than that.
不尽于此
This is a military situation. We should attack now.
现在已经进入军事态势了, 我们应该出击
No. I will not be responsible for starting a war.
不, 我不会担上发动战争的责任
There is one thing worse than war, Madam President
and that is defeat.
但比战争更糟糕的事情是失败, 总统夫人
You must think of your own position.
你必须得考虑自己的位子了
What about my position?
我的位子怎么了
If you're not seen to act decisively against the Draconians,
如果大家觉得你对龙族人没有果断的行动
you can and will be replaced.
你就可能被替换掉, 也将会被替换掉
(SCOFFING)
By you perhaps?
看来是被你?
We used to be friends once.
我们曾经是朋友
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
I know what's happened has changed all that,
我知道刚发生的这些改变了这一切
but do you really think I'd betray you?
但你真的认为我背叛了你?
No. No. I've never doubted you.
不, 不, 我从没怀疑过你
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
There are certain senior officers who feel
有一些高级官员认为
that a military dictatorship is needed.
现在需要进行军事独裁
Your political opponents are clamouring for war.
你的政治对手正在鼓吹战争
You must act now or they will bring you down.
你必须有所行动, 否则他们会把你拉下马
I shall break off diplomatic relations.
我会断绝外交关系
The Draconian Ambassador and his staff
will be expelled from this planet.
龙族大使和他的随从会被驱逐出这个星球
I shall inform the Emperor
that his actions will no longer be tolerated.
我将会告知皇帝我们不会再容忍他的这些行动
But unless you give me conclusive evidence about their intentions,
但前提是你得给我关于他们企图的确切证据
I shall not strike the first blow.
我不能先开第一枪
The proof you need is in the minds of those two traitors.
你想要的证据就在那两个叛徒的脑袋里
We shall have to use the mind probe.
我们不得不使用思维探测器了
Not on the girl.
饶过那个女孩儿吧
- Perhaps I can make her see reason. - I doubt that.
- 也许我可以让她明白理由 - 我表示怀疑
I prefer to put my faith in the mind probe.
我更倾向于把我的信心放到思维探测器上
WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor, shall we try again?
怎样, 博士, 我们再试试?
You can suit yourself.
请自便
But I warn you, you're wasting your time.
但我警告你, 你是在浪费自己的时间
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of the Draconian Secret Service?
你是不是龙族特勤组的一员?
No.
不是
No change in the rhythm, sir. He must be telling the truth.
没有波动, 他说的应该是实话
How did you get on the cargo ship?
你怎么到货船上去的?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
我是坐着我自己的飞船过去的, TARDIS
- TARDIS? - Yes, my own spaceship.
- TARDIS? - 是的 我的飞船
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians attack the cargo ship?
为什么你们要帮助龙族人攻击那艘货船?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
我没有
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians, it was the Ogrons.
而且, 那也不是龙族人, 是 Ogrons
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly.
Or else he's controlling it.
你的机器工作不正常, 要不然就是他可以控制它
We've checked all the circuits, sir. Those are his thoughts.
我们都检查过所有线路了, 先生. 这就是他的想法
We know this man is a Draconian agent. He must be lying.
我们知道这个人是一个龙族特工, 他肯定在撒谎
Perhaps he's already been brainwashed, sir.
或许他已经被洗脑了, 先生
But as far as he's concerned, what he's telling us is the truth.
但就他现在而言, 他告诉我们的是实情
Then we must break through his conditioning.
那我们必须攻破他的防线
Unless you tell me the truth, the real truth,
除非你告诉我们实情, 真正的实情
I shall be forced to use increased power.
我只能被迫加大功率了
I wouldn't do that, old man.
我也不愿意这么做, 老头
I know these machines. They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
我了解这些机器, 他们并不是太可靠, 知道不?
You'd do better to worry about the effects on your mind.
你还是操心一下它对你的影响吧
There's just no telling some people, is there, my dear?
有些人就是完全没有判断力, 是吧
Step up the power.
调大功率
Increase to 12.
加大到12
Now!
现在!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
你是龙族特工吗?
- DOCTOR: No. - When do they plan to attack us?
- 不是   - 他们打算什么时候开始攻击?
They don't.
他们不会
- How did you board the cargo ship? - Through the TARDIS.
- 你是如何到货船上去的? - 通过 TARDIS
- Who first recruited you to serve the Draconians? - No one.
- 谁招募你服务于龙族人的?   - 没谁
WILLIAMS: Who are the other Draconian agents on Earth?
地球上的龙族特工都还有谁?
I don't know.
我不知道
WILLIAMS: The truth, man. I want the truth.
实情, 我要的实情
- I'm telling you the truth. - WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
- 我说的就是实情    - 我会得到实情的
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
博士, 你确定你没事吗?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
当然, 只是有一点头疼
I like the new outfit. Who are you fighting tonight?
我对结果挺满意. 你今晚在跟谁斗?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
你那边发生了什么?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
哦, 他们一直逼迫我坦白
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
是, 很难堪啊, 对不?
Well, they've made up their minds, you see.
他们自己的想法早就先入为主了, 你看
They'll only believe us if we tell them what they want to hear.
只有我们说他们想听的, 他们才会相信我们
It's a pity really that the Ogrons didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Ogrons 没能成功绑架我们, 还真是遗憾啊
Perhaps we should have been more helpful.
也许那样我们还能更有用一些
- Why?  - Well, if they had succeeded,
- 为什么 - 这样, 如果他们成功了
presumably they'd have taken us to where the TARDIS is.
应该说来他们会把我们带到 TARDIS 所在之处
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
抱歉, Jo
but I'm afraid another kidnapping attempt is our only ray of hope.
不过恐怕再来一次绑架才是我们唯一的希望
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
所以, 我们就只能干坐在这里, 等着那些搞笑的 Ogrons 出现?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
正是如此
The President wants to see you. Get moving.
总统要见你, 走吧
Not you. You.
不是你, 是你
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
这可能是你的机会, 好运
- See you later. - Bye.
- 晚些见   - 拜
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance to tell me the truth.
我给你最后一次机会, 你告诉我真相
Madam President,
总统夫人
I've been telling you the truth for some considerable time
我一直在告诉你真相, 颇有一段时间了
but you just won't believe me.
但你就是我相信我
I can't think why you chose to work for the Draconians.
我想不通你为什么选择去为龙族人卖命
But whatever it is, I'll double any offer they've made to you.
不管怎样吧, 他们给你许诺了什么, 我都加倍
That's very generous of you, madam,
夫人, 您真是慷慨
but you'd only be buying information that doesn't exist.
但这是在买不存在的信息
You leave me no alternative.
你让我没有选择了
Under the powers invested in me by the Special Security Act,
根据特别安全法案授权于我的权力
I'm sending you to the Lunar Penal Colony.
我现在发配你去月球刑事殖民地
What, without a trial?
什么, 不进行审判吗?
Without even a chance to state my case?
甚至都不给我一个陈述的机会?
So, you're just tucking me quietly away, are you?
你们就这样把我悄悄地处理了, 是吧?
What about my companion?
我的同伴会怎样?
She will remain here.
她将留在这里
I have hopes that, away from your influence,
我还是有所期待, 远离了你的影响
I might be able to make her see the error of her ways.
我也许能让她看明白她走错了路
But you will see that she comes to no harm?
但你可否盯着点, 让她免受伤害?
We are not barbarians.
我们不是野蛮人
If you want to help her,
如果你想帮她,
why don't you tell me where she comes from?
为什么不告诉我她来自哪里?
I'd like to inform her family.
我好通知她的家人
I'd like to, madam.
我也期望如此, 夫人
I really would, but there's nothing that I can say
that you'd believe.
我真的这样, 但确实我说不出什么你能相信的东西
May I say goodbye to her?
我可以跟她道个别吗?
No! You'll be leaving immediately for the penal colony.
不, 你要立刻出发去刑事殖民地
We're putting you where
your Draconian friends will be unable to reach you.
我们要把你放到你那些龙族朋友够不到你的地方
Over there.
过去
Get in line and face the front!
去排好队, 面朝前面
Face the front!
面朝前面
(PATEL SIGHING)
What did they get you for?
他们为什么抓你?
Oh, it's a long story.
哦, 说来话长
I don't think you'd believe me even if I told you.
我不觉得你会信, 即便我告诉你
You are a political, aren't you?
你是一个政客, 对吧?
- Not particularly, no.  - Oh, come off it!
- 并不是, 不  - 哦, 得了
Only politicals get sent to the Moon,
none of your common criminals.
只有政治犯才会被送到月球来, 每一个是普通犯罪分子
Have you got many political prisoners here?
你们这里有很多政治犯吗?
Thousands. Well, I mean,
上千. 我是说,
criticise the government and you're for it, aren't you?
批评政府, 你就进来了, 是吧
You a member of the Peace Party?
你是和平党成员?
Well, you might put it like that, yes.
这个, 如果你这么想的话, 是的
Yes, I tried to stop a war.
是的, 我试图阻止一场战争
Me too. I tried to sabotage a military base.
我也是, 我试图破坏一个军事基地
Did you? How long is your sentence?
是吗? 你被判了多久?
Sen... Where have you been?
判了...你从哪儿来的啊?
There are no sentences.
根本就没有审判
Once they send you to the Moon, it's forever.
一旦他们把你发配来月球, 就是终身的
(DOOR OPENING)
- No talking! - Get in line!
- 不许说话!   - 站成一排
What have you got in there?
你这里有什么
- Nothing.  - Show me.
- 什么也没有  - 拿出来
Chocolate.
巧克力
My allowance from the remand prison.
我从监狱领到的津贴
No chocolate allowed here.
这里不允许有巧克力
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Now that's stealing, you know.
你这是偷窃, 知道吗
That's what I'm in for. Got a troublemaker, have we?
我进来就为这个. 看来我们有个刺头啊, 是吗?
That's what I'm in for.
我进来就为这个
- I'll remember you. - Good, I'm glad to hear it.
- 我会记住你的  - 很好, 听见这句话我很高兴
LUNAR GUARD: Attention!
立正!
CROSS: New arrivals, sir.
新来的, 长官
I'm the Governor of this penal colony.
我是本刑事殖民地的监狱长
There's one rule here, you do as you're told.
这里就一条规则: 服从指令
If you behave yourselves, you'll be reasonably treated,
如果表现良好, 就能得到合理对待
but you have no rights and there is no means of escape.
但你们没有任何权利, 也没有任何路子逃跑
You'll do well to remember
that you're here for the rest of your lives.
你们都得牢牢记住, 你的下半辈子都得在这里了
Why is that man not in uniform?
为什么那个人没有穿囚服?
Don't know, sir. That's how they sent him.
不知道, 长官. 他们送他来就这样
Special security prisoner.
是特别安全局的囚犯
- See he's kitted out immediately. - Sir.
- 赶紧给他换上 - 是
We won't be staying here forever, you know!
我们并不会一直在这里呆下去, 你知道吗?
The Peace Party will win one day.
有一天和平党会赢的
Very well, Cross, I'll leave them to you.
很好, Cross, 我把他们留给你了
Sir.
长官
That's probably the last time you'll see the Governor.
这可能是你们最后一次看见监狱长
But you'll see me every day.
但你们会每天都见到我的
Now I run a nice, quiet, tidy section here.
我这个区域一向都是和谐,安静,整洁的
Any trouble, it's a black mark on my records,
惹任何麻烦, 我的小本上就多一条黑记录
so there's never any trouble, got it?
所以不要惹麻烦, 明白吗?
Look, don't you realise you're one of us?
看, 你没发现你也是我们的一员吗?
We're all prisoners here! Victims of the system!
我们都是这里的囚犯! 是体系的受害者!
Belt up, you!
系好了, 你!
You, kit out that man. Come with me.
你, 给他发套囚服. 跟我来
I thought you said there were no common criminals here?
我记得你说过这里没有普通罪犯?
(PATEL SIGHING)
Cross is a trusty.
Cross 还算靠得住
They are all hardcore criminals
specially imported from other prisons.
他们都是真正的罪犯, 从其他监狱转过来的
Professor Dale?
Dale 教授?
You were on our youth committee, were you not?
你是我们青年团的, 对不?
(LAUGHING) That's right, sir.
对的, 先生
Oh, we met last year, just before your arrest.
我, 我们去年见过, 就在你被捕之前
Well, you'll find yourself in very good company here, my boy.
好, 看来你在这里找到了好伙伴, 孩子
I sometimes think there are more members of the Peace Party up here
我有时在想, 这里的和平党人数可能更多
than back on Earth.
比地球多
(PATEL LAUGHING)
Don't any of you ever try to escape?
你们没试过逃跑吗?
Escape? Occasionally. Why do you ask?
逃跑? 偶尔吧. 你为什么问这个?
- It seems a perfectly natural question.
- Do you know this man?
- 很自然的问题啊  - 你认识这个人吗?
Uh, no, sir. I met him on the shuttle.
哦, 不认识, 先生. 我是在穿梭船上碰上他的
I'd better get you a uniform. Come this way.
我还是给你拿一套囚服吧, 这边来
PRESIDENT: There's no doubt about it. These are the same people.
毫无疑问, 这是同一个人
No doubt. But that doesn't mean we should hand them over to anyone.
无疑. 但这也并不意味着我们应该把他们交给任何人
(BEEPING)
(SIGHING) I'm surprised, especially about the girl.
我觉得奇怪, 尤其是这个女孩儿
All these crimes!
看这些罪行!
Just the sort of people the Draconians would employ.
正是龙族人会招募的那种
Nevertheless, the dominion government of Sirius 4
does have a claim to them.
不管怎样, 天狼星4号星球政府要求引渡他们
And so do we. They have vital information.
我们也要这两个人. 他们有太重要的信息
They must be very important to them.
这些信息看来对他们也很重要
I think I'd better see their representative.
我想还是先见一下他们的代表
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
Send in the Commissioner from Sirius 4, please.
请将天狼星4号的专员请进来
Surely you're not going to hand them over?
你当然不会把他们交出去吧?
Well, we'll have to see, won't we?
嗯, 我们得看看情况, 是不?
Relationships with the colony of planets are always difficult.
星球殖民地之间的关系总是比较棘手
And if there is a war,
we'll need all the allies we can get, won't we?
如果要打一场战争, 我们得争取更多的盟友, 对吧
(DOOR OPENING)
The Commissioner, madam.
专员来了, 夫人
Madam President, this is indeed a great honour.
总统夫人, 这真是莫大的荣幸
(SIGHING) Check and mate.
将军
注: 这立体象棋真的不是抄自＜星级迷航＞吗 :-)
DALE: Yes, there's an excellent library.
是的, 这里有个不错的图书馆
There are books, videofilms, handicrafts and discussion groups,
有书, 有电影, 有工艺品, 还有讨论组
all sorts of ways of passing the time.
各种消磨时间的方法
Including planning to escape?
也能讨论逃跑计划吗?
That's not one of the things we discuss.
那可不是我们能讨论的话题
Oh, why? Doesn't anybody ever try?
哦, 为什么? 甚至都没有人尝试过?
Occasionally. There was an attempt last month.
偶尔吧. 上个月就有人企图越狱
Yes, what did happen?
对了, 结局怎样?
What always happens, they are dead.
总是一样, 他们都死了
No one escapes from here.
没人能从这里逃跑
No. No, quite so.
不, 不, 的确
But there's got to be a first time for everything, hasn't there?
但任何事总有个第一次, 对吧
Come on, Professor, come and tell me all you know about the layout here.
来吧, 教授, 来跟我说说这里的布局
Truly, Madam President, I...
真的, 总统夫人, 我...
I sympathise with your position.
我同情您的处境
But my government has sought these criminals throughout the galaxy.
但我的政府在搜索这些罪犯, 把整个星系搜了个遍
They are now prisoners of the government of Earth.
他们现在是地球政府的囚犯
That's good enough.
这就足够了
With the greatest respect, General Williams, I must disagree.
带着极大的敬意, Williams 将军, 我必须不同意
They are citizens of Sirius 4.
他们是天狼星4号的臣民
Part of Earth's empire.
那也是地球帝国的一部分
Yes, but it has been granted dominion status.
是的, 但它已经被授权可以自治
He has a point, General Williams.
他说得有点道理, Williams 将军
Once a colony has been raised to dominion status,
一旦殖民地被授予自治权
it enjoys certain autonomous rights,
它就应该享有这份权利
including the right to try and punish its own citizens.
这也包括审判和惩罚它自己臣民的权利
Exactly. But I feel sure that once these two have come to trial,
正是. 但我很肯定, 一旦这两个人被审判了之后
my government will be only too happy to send them back to you
我们政府会很乐意将他们送回来
for further interrogation.
以便你们进一步审讯
But, meanwhile, my orders are clear.
但与此同时, 我收到的命令也是很清楚的,
I must take them back with me to Sirius 4.
我必须把他们带回天狼星4号
I will not hand over vital prisoners to some tin-pot colony!
我不会把这么重要的囚犯交给某个破烂殖民地
As the commissioner has pointed out, General Williams,
正如专员所指出的, Williams 将军,
Sirius 4 is no longer a colony. It is a dominion.
天狼星4号已经不是一个殖民地了, 它是一个主权国
Your request is granted.
你的请求被批准了
Madam President, I am most grateful.
总统夫人, 我由衷感激
Heaven help you if you let them escape!
如果你让他们逃跑的话, 让老天帮你吧
You may rest assured, General Williams,
你可以回去休息了, Williams 将军
they will be perfectly safe with me.
他们跟我在一起非常安全
Right, keep it moving!
好了, 往前走
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Is this all we get?
我们就只能得到这个?
It contains all the elements to support life.
这东西包含了能支撑生命的所有要素
Mmm, and absolutely nothing to make it enjoyable, eh?
唔, 但完全没考虑把它做得讨喜一点, 是吧
You get used to it after a month or two.
你过一两个月就习惯了
Anyway, it's all we ever get.
不管怎么说, 我们只能得到这个
- Keep moving! - You heard him, move!
- 继续往前走!  - 你听到了, 走!
Not exactly friendly, are they?
他们一点也不友好, 是吧
One gets used to it.
早就习惯了
What time do we get to bed?
我们什么时候上床呢?
Anytime. There's no day or night here.
随时. 这里没有白天黑夜
No. Uh, tell me, Professor, when...
不, 嗷. 告诉我, 教授, 什么时候...
When do you plan to escape?
你打算什么时候逃跑?
No one escapes from here.
没人能从这里逃跑
But you're going to try?
但你还是要试?
For all I know, you could be a spy for the Governor.
就我所知的情况, 你可能是监狱长派来的奸细
If I were, I'd hardly be drawing attention to myself
如果我是, 我会这么着急地显露自己吗
quite so quickly, now would I?
会吗?
No, a valid point of logic.
不会. 有点道理
I wonder if I can trust you?
我在想, 能不能信任你
You've little or no alternative, Professor.
你的选择很少, 或者说没有, 教授
We're all in this sector together.
我们都在这个片区
Whatever you do, I shall know about it.
不管你做什么, 我都会知道
Yes, but we don't know you.
是的, 但我们不了解你
Why did they send you here?
他们为什么把你送进来?
Oh, I was sent here at the express wish of
a certain General Williams.
哦, 某个 Williams 将军一声令下, 我就被送到这里来了
We have no proof of that.
我们没有见到证据
We have no reason to tell you anything.
我们没有理由把什么都告诉你
I'll tell you something.
我跟你说
There is a conspiracy to start a war between Earth and Draconia.
现在有一场阴谋, 要挑起地球与龙族之间的战争
There are warmongers on both sides. We are aware of that.
两边都有一些好战分子, 这我们很清楚
But there's also a third party, Professor,
但还有一个第三方, 教授
who's plotting to set the two empires at each other's throats.
他的阴谋已经让两个帝国相互掐住了咽喉
No, I'll see her alone.
不, 我要单独见她
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
好久不见 (fixme), Grant 小姐?
You! What are you doing here?
你! 你在这里干什么?
To coin a phrase, I've come to take you away from all this.
简单地说, 我来带你远离这一切
What are you talking about?
你这是什么意思
Well, surely you don't want to
spend the rest of your life in here, do you?
你当然不会期望在这里过完你的下半辈子, 是吧?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you, that's for sure.
这是当然. 但我也不打算同你去任何地方
Oh, but you are, you know.
你会的, 知道吗
Believe it or not,
不管你信不信
I am a fully accredited commissioner from the planet Sirius 4
我现在是天狼星4号的完全授权的专员
and you and the Doctor are two dangerous criminals
而你和博士是两个危险的罪犯
being handed over into my custody.
要转交到我的手中
So it was you!
原来是你!
You ordered those Ogrons to attack the ships
是你命令了那些 Ogrons 来攻击那艘货船
and pretend they were Draconians!
还让他们假装是龙族人!
But, of course!
不过, 当然了
Those lumbering idiots could never have thought up
那些愚蠢的家伙是无论如何也想不出
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
如此天才的计划的
Why did you want to start a war?
你为什么要挑起一场战争?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
得了, Grant 小姐, 理性一点
You want to see the Doctor again, don't you?
你还想再见到博士的, 对吧?
- Where is he? - He's in another prison, on the Moon.
- 他在哪儿?  - 他现在在另外一个监狱, 月球上
We're going to collect him.
我们要去接他
How do I know you're telling the truth?
我怎么知道你说的是不是实话?
You don't.
你不知道
And the only way you'll find out is by coming with me.
唯一搞明白的方法就是跟我走
Well?
怎样
(SIGHING)
How did you know we were here in the first place?
你怎么知道我们在这里的?
Well, after they'd attacked the cargo ships,
啊, 当那些 Ogrons 攻击了那艘货船之后
the Ogrons returned to their planet, taking their loot with them.
他们带着战利品, 回到自己的星球
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
想想一下我的惊讶, 还有喜悦
when I found that they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
我发现他们带回来了博士的 TARDIS
And why are you taking us with you?
那你现在为什么要让我们跟你走?
Oh, need you ask?
哦, 这还需要说?
How could I leave two dear friends in such dire straits?
我怎么可能把两个亲爱的朋友留在这么恐怖的地方?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
哦, 你才不是这么想的
I'm going to believe that you want to help us...
我都要相信你是想帮助我们...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant, I have my reasons.
不管你信不信, Grant 小姐, 我有我的理由
Now, are you coming,
现在, 你是跟着走呢?
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
还是打算真在这个洞里耗完下半辈子?
Very well. I'll come.
好吧, 我去
Excellent!
太棒了!
The prisoner and I are ready to leave now, guard.
囚犯和我打算现在离开, 守卫
Anywhere is better than here.
任何地方都比这里好
DOCTOR: Well, there you are. There you have it.
诺, 就是这样, 你听到啦
That's how I came to be here.
这就是我怎么来到这里的
It's fantastic!
太神奇了!
I mean, our people seeing Draconians,
你看, 我们的人看见的是龙族人
Draconians seeing Earthmen. I can't believe it.
龙族人看见的是地球人, 我简直不敢相信
Well, I can.
不过呢, 我信
Good grief.
感谢老天
Do you know, sir, you're the first person who's believed me?
你知道吗, 先生, 你是第一个相信我的
It would explain a great deal.
这样很多事情就说得通了
After the stupidity of he Draconian war,
那场愚蠢的龙族战争结束之后
the bitterness eventually died down and we had many years of peace.
苦痛渐渐退去, 我们有了多年的和平
There were trade treaties, cultural exchanges
也有了商贸协定, 文化交流
and then, for no reason at all, these sudden acts of hostility.
然后, 没有任何缘由, 突然出现了这些敌对行为
(DOOR OPENING)
Dale! Over here!
Dale! 过来
- Yes, what is it?  - Spot check. You ought to know.
- 好, 什么事?  - 检查, 你自己知道
If you'll excuse me, one of our little prison rituals.
抱歉先离开一会, 有个监狱小仪式
This is it. There's a VIP landing on this spaceship
机会来了, 马上会有一艘VIP飞船降落
in 10 minutes' time, Bay 7.
只有10分钟了, 7号站
You can pinch it. I've set up two spacesuits for you.
你得抓紧了, 我已经给你们准备好了两套宇航服
I can't believe it.
简直不敢相信
Well, I keep my promises, now you keep yours.
好, 我说到做到, 你也要主动哦傲
When you get back to Earth, don't forget who your friends are.
等你回到地球, 别忘了谁是你的朋友
When the Peace Party takes over, you will be given a free pardon,
等和平党掌权了, 你会被赦免的
you have my word.
我承诺
Right, you're clean. Report to Air lock 3 for maintenance work.
好, 没什么东西. 3号减压舱需要维修, 去报道吧
You and one other. You can choose him yourselves, okay.
你, 再带一个人, 你可以自己选, 好吧
- DOCTOR: What is it? What's up? - Oh,just a search.
- 怎样, 有什么事?  - 哦, 只是搜查一下
All part of the routine.
都是经常的事儿了
(DOOR CLOSING)
Come on, Professor. Come on!
得了, 教授! 说吧!
You were giving off conspiracy in waves over there.
你们在那边肯定密谋了什么
You can trust me, you know.
你可以相信我的, 你知道的
The escape plan, it's now.
逃跑计划, 开始了
We have to walk from the air lock, across the Moon's surface.
我们必须先走到减压舱去, 从月球表面过去
We're going to steal a spaceship.
They've left two spacesuits for us.
我们要偷一艘飞船. 他们留了两件宇航服
Who are you taking with you?
你打算带谁走?
Well, I had planned to take another member
of the Peace Party committee
本来, 我是计划再带一位和平党成员的
but I'm afraid he'll have to give up his place.
但恐怕他得放弃他的位子了
Doctor, I want you to come with me.
博士, 我想你跟我一起走
Well, that's very generous of you, but...
啊, 那你真是太慷慨了, 不过...
We must get you back to Earth so that you can tell your story.
我们必须把你弄回地球, 这样你就可以把你的故事讲出去
Well, it was telling my story on Earth
呵呵, 正是在地球上讲我的故事
that got me sent here in the first place.
才把我送到这里来的
We have contacts everywhere,
我们跟各方都有联系
journalists, broadcasters, even friends in the government.
新闻记者, 主持人, 就是政府里面也有朋友
We'll make them believe you.
我们会让他们相信你的
Thank you, Professor.
谢谢你, 教授
You don't know what it means to me to have found allies at last.
你不知道, 终于找到盟友对我来说意味着什么
Well, we'd better be going, Doctor.
好, 我们得走了, 博士
This spaceship will be landing any moment.
飞船马上就要降落了
Good! He's left it open.
好, 他给留门了
Excellent! Excellent!
太好了, 太好了!
Come on, Doctor, we haven't got long.
快点, 博士, 我们没有太多时间
Take this one?
穿上这个?
We can't use the main entrance to the spaceport.
我们不能从太空港的主入口过去
It's too well guarded.
那里守卫严密
All we have to do is to walk across the Moon's surface,
我们要做的, 就是从月球表面穿过去
about 10 minutes and we're there.
大概10分钟我们就到了
Tell me, Professor, why is Cross helping you?
告诉我, 博士, 为什么 Cross 会帮你?
A kind of bribery, I'm afraid.
这算是一种行贿, 恐怕是
I promised to get him a free pardon once we get into power.
我承诺他说, 一旦我们掌权了, 会给他一个赦免
That's extraordinary.
I would have thought he would have wanted something
这很特别啊. 我原以为他想要的东西很难给呢
far more positive than promises.
没想到一个承诺就搞定了
DALE: Oh, he's not a bad fellow when you get to know him.
哦, 他倒不是个坏人, 如果你了解他的话
I appealed to his better self.
我激发了他善良的那一面
Now do hurry, Doctor.
得赶紧了, 博士
(ZIPPER FASTENING)
(AIR HISSING)
What's that? I thought I heard something.
什么声音? 我觉得我听到了什么
Yes. Now, Doctor,
是. 现在, 博士
clip my cylinder on the back of my suit
and then I'll fix up yours.
在我后背挂一下氧气瓶, 然后我来挂你的
DOCTOR: All right.
好的
- Well, this one's empty. - It can't be.
- 咦, 这个是空的  - 不可能
Well, it certainly is. Take a look for yourself.
喏, 就是空了. 你自己看看
There, look at the gauge.
这里, 看这个读数
Yes, and so is this one.
是, 这一个也是
They're both empty, Professor.
这两个都是空的, 教授
(AIR HISSING)
The door, it's locked!
这门, 被锁住了
- Listen. - They're depressurising.
- 听  - 他们正在减压
Don't you understand, man, they're pumping out the air!
你不明白吗, 朋友, 他们正在往外排空气!